This time we are in the mighty Dubai, in the United Arab Emirates , in the middle east
It's uh stinking hot here, it's not humid it's, it's kinda nice
Still you can definitely feel it
I'm in this weirdly vertical city
For a tech conference that Thoughtworks have sent me to
They paid for everything, flights accomodation and the ticket to enter
So that's pretty cool!
Today we have to start with the mighty tallest building in the world the Burj
Of course you know we're going up
Build up cause they can't possibly build out
I'm keen for that fountain show
That city is absolutely. fucking. bussing.
It's conference day!
I'm a delegate, dunno what that means
Guess I'll look around
I'm checking out the Zabeel park, right beneath the Dubai Frame
Then hopefully we're gonna go up the frame
And then checkout the Glowing Garden
Have you ever seen a public park that you entered using a
Tap and go, public transport card
Well now I have
That.. Doesn't look real
Such a weird thing to see
Let me in
Let me in!
I really just gotta, I just gotta
It's walkable glass
Nuh
Well that was pretty cool and only a couple of bucks
And this is The Glowing Gardens
Yayyyy
Aw
Oil pumps
Totally reasonable, for Dubai
Hwuh, Not your climate friends
Ludicrous speed!
Well, I really enjoyed this little park
It's, such a nifty little thing, it's huge
Anyway, next up I guess
So today I'm out in the desert
About a good two hours from Dubai
Near the border with Oman
For a day of fun in the sun
Be doing some quadbiking, some sandsurfing, camel riding
And probably getting sunburnt, Let's go!
What a unit
Not bad, not bad at all
We're ah, off roading? Four wheel driving?
Flat tyres..?
Shit
Hello
Hello Australia
(Unintelligible) Dubai?
Let's go!
Woooo!
Camels how ya dune?
Yeah yeah trust me
Trust you? Wayy
Oh what is this?
Shit
What better way, to juxtapose the desert
Than with the snow? That's right
I'm still in the U.A.E, infact I'm in a mall
Where they have an indoor skiing centre
But yeah how cool's that? And it's like, pretty affordable
Here it was a hundred bucks, not bad
With gear
Let's go hit the slopes
Look at my long pole!
Yesss
Perfect, yep
Slow?
That means fast
Not behd
There's not just skiing around here there's a few other things, like this one
Pingu
Yes jump in
Have a good one
My ass!
Yeah I'd do that again
Today I'm at Al Seef
Which is kinda like, South Bank of Dubai
It's old Dubai, a lot of the buildings around here are really old
The city used to be a fishing village
Nowadays it's kinda like a heritage
There's shops but no one running them
I'm starting to think maybe it's like a prayer time right now
Could use a motor, or
Oar
Naw this is fantastic
Unfettered capitalism wins again
Don't even need a helmet
That is the discount flap thingy they have ziptied to the handlebars
[Sigh]
On the ferry, heading around the top of the coast line
Is it just me or does a lot of these building look very empty?
Can't believe I forgot my telescope at home but you can kinda tell
Apparently I saved 50% by buying a ticket 2 minutes before the "sunset tax" comes in so..
Let's have a look
Well, so comes the end of yet another trip
Been an excellent, 6ish days
I've done nothing, really, except tour around
Fricken sweat
Sweat and breathe fumes
And I reckon one day if I ever came back one day with money it would be a completely different experience
But for this time, thanks Dubai it's been great
Seeya next time
It's gettin a bit loud
Oh my god
ahh
Ahhhhh
AHH